connecting these two line segments of
length one produces a line segment of
length root2 draw a circle of radius one
at the end of that line segment draw
perpendicular to that line segment and
this produces a line segment of length
root three you can continue repeating
this process over and over again drawing
a circle of radius one drawing a
perpendicular to the previous line
segment and then the new line segment
will have a length given by the square
root of the next integer so here we've
constructed the length < TK of two up to
< TK of 7 repeating this process over
and over produces a spiral shape known
as the spiral of theodoris we can use
this spiral to construct lengths of sare
root of n for any n that we want where N
is a positive integer just using a
straight edge and a compass for example
as we keep spiraling out here we'll end
with a line segment whose length is < TK
of 200 do you think you could construct
this by hand